- 快速分词器
- The fast tokenizers
变形金刚图书馆的速度很快，
of the Transformers library are fast,
但他们也实现了非常有用的功能
but they also implement features that will be super useful
用于数据预处理和后处理。
for data pre-processing and post-processing.
让我们来看看吧！
Let's have a look at them!
首先，让我们来看看
First, let's have a look
在分词器的通常输出中。
at the usual output of a tokenizer.
我们得到对应于 token 的输入 ID，
We get input IDs that correspond to token,
但是我们在这个过程中丢失了很多信息。
but we lose a lot of information in the process.
例如，
For instance,
这里两个句子的标记化是相同的
here the tokenization is the same for the two sentences
即使一个比另一个多几个空间。
even if one has several more spaces than the other.
因此，仅仅拥有输入 ID 是不够的
Just having the input IDs is thus not enough
如果我们想将一些标记与一段文本相匹配，
if we want to match some tokens with a span of text,
我们需要做的事情
something we'll need to do
例如，在处理问题回答时。
when tackling question answering, for instance.
也很难知道
It's also difficult to know
当两个标记是否属于同一个词时。
when two tokens belong to the same word or not.
当你只看输出时看起来很容易
It looks easy when you just look at the output
一个 BERT 分词器，我们只需要看一下
of a BERT tokenizer where we just need to look
对于散列散列。
for the hash hash.
但是其他分词器有不同的方式
But other tokenizers have different ways
标记部分单词。
to tokenize parts of words.
例如，RoBERTa 添加了这个特殊的 G 符号
For instance, RoBERTa adds this special G symbol
在单词的开头标记标记
to mark the tokens at the beginning of the word
T5 使用这个特殊的下划线符号
and T5 uses this special underscore symbol
为了同样的目的。
for the same purpose.
值得庆幸的是，快速分词器会跟踪这个词
Thankfully, the fast tokenizers keep track of the word
每个令牌来自，
each token comes from,
使用 word_ids 方法，你可以在它们的输出上使用。
with a word_ids method you can use on their outputs.
输出不一定清楚，
The output is not necessarily clear,
但像这样聚集在一张漂亮的桌子上，
but assembled together in a nice table like this,
我们可以查看每个标记的单词位置。
we can look at the word position for each token.
更好的是，快速标记器会跟踪
Even better, the fast tokenizers keep track
每个标记来自的字符范围，
of the span of characters each token comes from,
我们可以在调用它时得到它们
and we can get them when calling it on one
或通过添加几个文本
or several text by adding
return_offsets_mapping=True 参数。
the return_offsets_mapping=True argument.
在这种情况下，我们可以看到我们是如何跳仓的
In this instance, we can see how we jump positions
在 hash hash token 和 super token 之间，
between the hash hash token and the super token,
因为首句中有多个空格。
because of the multiple spaces in the initial sentence.
为了实现这一点，快速分词器
To enable this, the fast tokenizers
在每一步存储附加信息
store additional information at each step
他们的内部管道。
of their internal pipeline.
该内部管道包括规范化，
That internal pipeline consists of normalization,
我们对文本进行一些清洁，
where we apply some cleaning to the text,
喜欢小写或删除口音；
like lower casing or removing the accents;
预标记化，
pre-tokenization,
这是我们将文本分成单词的地方；
which is where we split the texts into words;
然后我们应用分词器的模型，
then we apply the model of the tokenizer,
这是单词被分成标记的地方，
which is where the words are split into tokens,
在最终进行后期处理之前，
before finally doing the post processing,
添加特殊标记的地方。
where special tokens are added.
从管道的开始到结束，
From the beginning to the end of the pipeline,
标记器跟踪每个文本范围
the tokenizer keeps track of each span of text
对应于每个单词，然后是每个标记。
that corresponds to each word, then each token.
我们会看到它有多有用
We'll see how useful it is
当我们处理以下任务时：
when we tackle the following tasks:
在进行掩码语言建模时
when doing masked language modeling
一种获得最先进结果的变体
one variation that gets state-of-the-art results
是屏蔽给定单词的所有标记
is to mask all the tokens of a given word
而不是随机选择的单词。
instead of randomly chosen words.
这将要求我们使用我们看到的单词 ID。
This will require us to use the word IDs we saw.
在做 token 分类的时候，
When doing token classification,
我们需要转换我们在单词上的标签，
we'll need to convert the labels we have on words,
每个标记上的标签。
to labels on each tokens.
至于偏移映射，
As for the offset mappings,
当我们需要转换时它会非常有用
it will be super useful when we need to convert
将句子中的标记位置转换为一段文本，
token positions in a sentence into a span of text,
我们在寻找时需要知道
which we'll need to know when we're looking
在回答问题时
at question answering
或者在对相应的标记进行分组时
or when grouping the tokens corresponding
到令牌分类中的同一实体。
to the same entity in token classification.
要查看这些任务，
To have a look at these tasks,
查看下面链接的视频！
check the videos linked below!